A Guide to the Booth Tarkington Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #7416-f
Booth Tarkington Collection 1907-1914
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
7416-f
24 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase [ 1971 Jul 14 ] 1971 Aug 5
Item Listing
- Letters
  - Booth Tarkington to James Whitcomb Riley, 1907 Aug 20; ALS, 2 p.
    [Expresses appreciation for Riley's poem and its dedication to himself; attributes his becoming a writer to Riley's influence; states that only his feeling that his books did not meet Riley's critical standards prevents him dedicating one to him.]
  - Booth Tarkington to James Whitcomb Riley, 1907 Aug 26; ALS, 2 p. w/env
    [Thanks Riley for an inscribed set of his collected works; writes that he will take them to Paris when he returns; compares the sensation of seeing such a handsome edition of a writer's work to that of an artist seeing all his paintings "well hung in some handsome gallery.]
  - Elizabeth B. Tarkington to James Whitcomb Riley, 1907 Nov 1; ALS, 2 p. w/env
    [Writes on behalf of the Managers of the Indianapolis Orphans Asylum to ask for financial support; describes the plight of the orphanage whose support has been cut by the General Assembly; hopes the citizens of Indianapolis will help or the children must be "turned out."]
  - Helena Tarkington to James Whitcomb Riley, 1907 Nov 28; ALS, 1 p. w/env
    [Expresses appreciation for his tribute to the "Old Glee Club" in
    The Reader
    thanks him for contribution and for friendship in a time of grief.]
  - Booth Tarkington to James Whitcomb Riley, 1907 Dec 4; ALS, 1 p. w/env
    [Feels greatly honored that his name will live on in Riley's book; writes it is a comforting thought as he is unsure of the worth of his own books.]
  - Louisa Tarkington to James Whitcomb Riley, [1908] Jan 20; ALS, 2 p. w/env
    [Requests inscription for photograph for Booth Tarkington to hang by his desk.]
  - John S. Tarkington to James Whitcomb Riley, [1908 Jul 27]; ALS, 1 p. w/env
    [Writes that he has learned from Cushing that Riley is from Boone, Indiana and wonders if his absence is explained by a trip to Boone. ]
  - Booth Tarkington to James Whitcomb Riley, [1911] May 2; ALS, 4 p. w/env
    [Expresses pleasure over recent visit; outlines plan for a small party to celebrate the hanging of Riley's portrait by [Wayman ?] Adams in the Tarkingtons' home; suggests inviting Mrs. Holstein, whose relief portrait of Riley he praises, Ed Howland, Hewitt Howland and their father, Carl McCullock, M. D.; discusses the merits of portraits of Riley by Sargent, Steele, and especially one by Adams.]
  - Unknown to James Whitcomb Riley, [1911 Aug 16]; ALS, 1 p. w/env
    [Describes reading "
    The Black People
    " to an invalid who liked everything except the conclusion; encloses last photograph of the deceased Gamin.]
  - Louisa Tarkington to James Whitcomb Riley, [1912] Jan 14; ALS, 2 p. w/env
    [Thanks him for "the beautiful Lockerbie Book."]
  - Booth Tarkington to James Whitcomb Riley, 1913 Apr 14; ALS, 3 p. w/env
    [Thanks him for praise of his work "
    The Flirt
    "; recalls his admiration, since boyhood, of Riley as creator and critic.]
  - [John S.] Tarkington to James Whitcomb Riley, 1913 Aug 12; ALS, 1 p. w/env
    [Thanks him for gift of candy, saying Linda [Tarkington] is "placated" for his absence while visiting Riley; she disclaims that statement and thanks him for the candy.]
  - Susannah Tarkington to James Whitcomb Riley, 1913 Oct 7; ALS, 5 p. w/env
    [Describes vacation in Maine, improvement in Booth Tarkington's health, visit of Haute, Donald and his nurse; discusses complications of feeding and housing such a diverse group; comments on Donald's remarkable recovery and Ovid's return; mentions plan to go to New York and Princeton before returning home; notes her pleasure reading "
    Bag and Baggage
    " and the "
    Lockerbie pieces
    . "]
  - Booth Tarkington to James Whitcomb Riley, 1914 Mar 16; ALS, 4 p. w/env
    [Thanks him for praise and grapefruit; describes conflict between Italian officer and German captain on a ship; comments on Riley's improved health; writes that work on Harper's series prevented travel; outlines Penrod story to appear in
    Metropolitan
    and describes movie written for Jimmy Hackett to be filmed in Paris.]
  - Susannah Tarkington to James Whitcomb Riley, Sep 10; ALS, 3 p. w/env
    [Regrets departure for Maine before Riley's return to Indiana; describes Booth Tarkington's good health and their expectation of staying in Maine until November.]
  - Booth Tarkington to James Whitcomb Riley, n. d.; ALS, 1 p. w/env
    [Invites him to a formal dinner with Mr. B., Mr. Doubleday and the "home-folks."]
  - Booth Tarkington to James Whitcomb Riley, n. d.; ALS, 1 p. w/env
    [Expects him at [The University] Club later in the day; write they will be joined by Stoker, Dr. Hays, and Laurence Irving. ]
  - John Tarkington to James [Whitcomb Riley], n. d.; ALS, 2 p.
    [Provides recipe for a fruit drink; sends 2 tumblers, lemons, and oranges; writes that the concoction will put him "knee deep in July"; suggests sharing with Bob Geiger's "Lizzie."]
  - Louisa Tarkington to James Whitcomb Riley, n. d.; ALS, 3 p. w/env
    [Thanks him for the package containing "
    The Raggedy Man
    " for Laurel and "
    The Boys of the Old Glee Club
    " for herself.]
- Photographs
  - Home of Booth Tarkington, with car, 1911 Jun; Photo
  - View of waves, 1913 Oct; Photo
    [Written on verso: "Surf at Kennebunkport. ]
  - John Tarkington, father of Booth Tarkington, seated, n. d.; Photo
    [Caption: "The most [illegible] Old Man."]
  - River scene, n. d.; Photo
    [Written on verso: "Sunset Rock -On the river."]
  - Shore scene, n. d.; Photo
    [Written on verso: "One of the many beautiful coves by the shore."]